

Phone: +61 434390783 Email: sliu178@gmail.com Website: http://samliu.me github: github.com/bzsamus

SUMMARY

I am a web developer specialized in frontend and backend developments, who is also capable of handling some server configuration works.

With over five years of experience in analyzing, developing and managing websites and web applications. I am a constant learner with the ability to be a team player as well as to work independently under self direction.

My ability to hit the ground running, together with my research, analysis and problem solving skills, can instantly benefit any development team.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Programming Languages: PHP, Python, Javascript, Objective C, HTML,

OOP, Design pattern

Database: MySQL, SQLite, MongoDB

Technologies & Tools: memcache, Codelgniter, Django, jQuery, smarty

Operating Systems: CentOS, FreeBSD, Windows, Mac OS

Web servers: Apache, lighttpd, nginx Data Mining: google analytic, kontagent Version Control: SVN,Git, Mercurial

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Freelancer, Saturday LLC., Taipei, Taiwan — 2011~Present

- Audio-Technica Taiwan (http://www.audio-technica.com.tw/)
 Worked with another freelance designer and helped client redesign and develop website using PHP, MySQL,Javascript,jQuery.
- Jellybird Company (http://www.jellybirdcompany.com/)
 The most important part of my job was to communicate with the client in order to understand their requirements, and to provide solutions within the required time frame and budget. Website developed using Wordpress for content management. Other pages are highly customized with facebook social plugin, open graph integration, SEO and analytic metrics.
- Tarot Yearcycle (http://itunes.apple.com/tw/app/ta-luo-liu-nian/id477137482?mt=8)
 An iPhone app developed as a personal side project using native Objective C.

Phone: +61 434390783 Email: sliu178@gmail.com Website: http://samliu.me github: github.com/bzsamus

Software Developer, meeya Inc., Taipei, Taiwan — 2008~2011

- Worked in a team of 4 developers. My main responsibility was to develop new features for social website meeya.cc using PHP and MySQL.
- Worked with a project manager and a designer, we created a PHP, MySQL based web game called "island7" in 4 weeks and launched on social website meeya.cc.
- The company I worked for act as a production house for advertising agencies, providing digital marketing solutions on facebook. I worked as R&D for facebook API's, social channels and open graph protocol. I have also created a system that used MVC framework(codeigniter and django) to quickly generate applications on facebook by making commonly used features as modules.
- Worked as the lead backend developer for facebook social game "StoreCity" https://apps.facebook.com/storecity_tw/. The team consist of 2 backend developers, 3 frontend flash developers, 1 hardware architect and 3 designers. My main role was to write backend core which required me to collaborate closely with frontend developers and the hardware architect. We used svn for version control and redmine for milestone planning and issue tracking. The backend was written in PHP and uses singleton, factory and adapter patterns. PHPUnit was used for unit testing.
- Lead developer for social game "StoreCity" cross platform deployment. Collaborated remotely with engineers from Rekoo China and Plinga Germany to deploy the game on mixi Japan, mobage Japan, Hyves Nederlands and Nasza Klasa Poland using OpenSocial protocol.

Software Developer, CoreLight Technology Co., Ltd., Taipei, Taiwan — 2007~2008

- Worked as a junior developer. My main role was to maintain, bug fix and add features to the exist LMS(Learning management system) platforms using PHP, MySQL and smarty.
- Implemented blog system & live broadcast channel into Shih Chien University Library website with another developer, using PHP and MySQL hosted on windows NT server. The blog was done using Drupal and live broadcast as a module.

EDUCATION

University of Auckland, New Zealand — BSc, Computer Science 2001~2003

Howick College, New Zealand 1996~2000

OTHER

- Participant of Yahoo! Open Hack Day Taiwan 2008 In a team of 3 developers we developed a photo tagging and categorize application for yahoo Taiwan's album service.
- Volunteer helper for Facebook Developer Garage Taipei 2009,2010